Such a shame...
真是丢人现眼…
But I applaud you, Megatron.
但我佩服你 威震天
You certainly made a grand exit.
连驾崩都这么有排场
Ah Soundwave, cue the audio visual.
啊 声波 启动视频会议
I wish to address the troops.
我想和士兵们讲两句
The loss of Megatron, leader of the great Decepticon uprising,
霸天虎大业未竟之际 威震天却突然离世
is certainly a blow to our cause.
这对我们来说无疑是一个打击
Yet we mustn't despair over his tragic... demise.
但我们绝不能因他的悲惨遭遇而感到绝望
But instead, embrace his ultimate sacrifice,
恰恰相反 我们要对他的壮烈牺牲表示拥护
and build upon the foundation he laid,
因为在他的遗体之上
with an even mightier hand.
有一个更加强大的身影
With all due respect, commander star... er, lord Starscream.
恕我直言 红蜘蛛指挥…呃 红蜘蛛陛下
Yes, yes. What is it?
说吧 说吧 什么事？
If we failed to conquer Earth under lord Megatron's command,
如果连威震天陛下都没能带领我们征服地球
what hope do we have now while the Autobots still defend it.
现在面对那些汽车人 我们还有多少胜算？
I studied for millennia, under our former master.
千万年来 我一直站在我们已故主人的身后
Thus I am equate to lead you.
统领你们绰绰有余
I, Megatron's true heir,
我 威震天的合法继承人
Lord Starscream, Emperor of Destruction!
红蜘蛛陛下 破坏大帝！
[Murmurs...]
这个…
What use our troops who can't arise to the task of inflicting unspeakable destruction in my name!
打着我的旗号却毫无斗志的士兵有何用！
legend tells of one capable warrior,
传说有个武艺超群的战士
one who exists here upon this very planet,
正巧此人就在这个星球上
one who can be student to my master.
应该可以让他唯我是从
Optimus, why so glum?
擎天柱 你怎么闷闷不乐？
This planet,
这颗星球…
all planets are finally free from Megatron's tyranny.
甚至所有星球 终于逃出了威震天的魔爪
I do not disagree, Ratchet.
我不否认 救护车
It's just, a small part of me hoped to change Megatron's mind,
只是 我比较倾向于改变威震天的意愿
not to extinguish his spark.
而不是消灭他的火种
Optimus, his vileness was not slain by your hand,
擎天柱！那个恶霸的死因不在于你
but by his own twisted arrogance.
而是因为他的狂妄自大！
I'm sorry,
很抱歉
I know the two of you have quite a history.
我知道你们两个交情很深
But the Megatron whom I once fought beside perished eons ago,
但那个曾和我并肩作战的威震天 很久之前就不在了
the day he chose to become a Decepticon.
一旦成为霸天虎 便不再回头
The Decepticons may be in disarray, but they aren't without leadership.
霸天虎现在可能军心涣散 但他们并非群龙无首
And while Starscream is no Megatron,
何况红蜘蛛不是威震天
he is far from predictable.
他从不按常理出牌
Decepticons!
霸天虎！
We are under attack!
我们遭到袭击！
It's no attack, Ratchet.
不是袭击 救护车
It's my volcano.
是我的火山
Was.
曾经是
Hold still Bulkhead,
别动 隔板！
Jupiter needs its red spot.
木星还少个大红斑
Woopsy.
又洒了
What... in the Allspark... is going on in here?
这…看在火种源的份上 到底在搞什么？！
Our projects are due tomorrow.
我们明天要交作业
Maybe we need one of these doohickeys.
可能还要装一个小东西
You are a motorcycle, Arcee.
你是摩托车 阿尔茜
Shouldn't you know how to build the motorcycle engine?
你难道不会制造摩托发动机吗？
You're a human, Jack.
你还是人类呢 杰克
Can you build me a small intestine?
你能造出小肠来吗？
But the science affairs are big parts of our grade.
但科学作业在成绩里占的比重很大
Yea! If Bulkhead doesn't help me finish this model of our solar system...
是啊！如果隔板不帮我把太阳系模型弄完…
Or Bumblebee of your volcanoes? Or...
大黄蜂见过你们的火山吗？还有…
...Arcee of our motorcycles?
…阿尔茜没见过摩托车吗？
Precisely! We're not earthlings!
说得对！我们不是地球人！
And they are not scientists.
他们也不是科学家
But the Autobots are their guardians, Ratchet.
但汽车人是他们的守护者 救护车
Would it hurt to learn more of earth by helping our young friends with their school work?
帮助我们的年轻朋友完成作业 顺便熟悉地球 何尝不可呢？
Well... Maybe our young friends should try learning more of Cybertron.
那…这些年轻朋友也应该熟悉一下塞博特恩
During the Great War,
大战期间
so much energon was hidden on this forsaken rock,
这个鬼地方贮藏了许多能量
that our departed master sent some of Cybertron's greatest to guard it.
我们的先帝派塞博特恩最棒的战士来守护它们
True warriors, now lying in stasis,
是真正的勇士 处于沉睡之中
waiting to be reawakened.
等待着被唤醒
Such folly that late in life,
威震天明知道时日不多
Megatron searched distant space for warriors,
还愚蠢地跑到太空深处去寻找战士
rather than here, beneath his feet.
却忽略了这里 就在他的脚下
What do you mean you can't pinpoint his signal?
你说无法找到他的信号 是什么意思？
I know we are close!
我知道就在附近！
Boost the power to your sensors!
把你的探测器功率加大！
Yesss... There...
是的…在那儿…
Really Bumblebee?
真的吗 大黄蜂？
Then how do you make warrior class?
那你是怎么进战士班的？
But I've seen you in action, you are awesome!
但我看过你打仗 身手不错的！
I second your opinion, Raf.
我也这么认为 拉夫
But Autobot life cycles are much longer than those of humans.
但汽车人的生命周期远比人类的要长
And though it may be hard to believe our young scout
说起来很难让你信服
still has much to experience.
但这位年轻的侦察员的确需要累积经验
Exposed energon, and it's on the move.
有能量外露 而且正在移动
And since we ain't moving it, guess who must be?
既然不是我们在动 猜猜会是谁？
Decepticons.
霸天虎
Without Megatron?
威震天不是死了吗？
Unfortunately Megatron's legacy will live on,
威震天是死了
as others rise to take his place.
但恐怕很多人想坐上他的宝座
Autobots, you have projects to complete.
汽车人 你们得完成作业
Ratchet, I may require aid.
救护车 我可能需要帮手
Science affair is a big part of their grade?
既然科学作业在他们的成绩里占的比重很大
Perhaps I'm better suited to remain behind and advise.
也许我最好留下来 给他们提点建议
Very well.
好吧
Bumblebee, let us see about this energon in transit.
大黄蜂 我们去看看这个会飞的能量
Excellent, Soundwave.
很好 声波
The cube.
能量块
The energon infusion,
注入的能量
it's working.
有效果了！
No Bumblebee, it does not.
不 大黄蜂 能量不会消失
Hold your position, and wait my command.
坚守岗位 等我的命令
Awaken, warrior,
苏醒吧 战士
rise and serve your new master.
醒过来 侍奉你的新主人！
Skyquake serves only one master.
天震只侍奉一个主人
Excellent,
很好
your loyalty and devotion will set a fine example for the troops.
你的忠诚和奉献精神将成为军队的好榜样
No need to be timid, Skyquake,
不必拘谨 天震
you may bow.
俯首称臣吧
You failed to grasp my meaning.
你没听懂我的话
I am here on a mission
派我来这里执行任务的
assigned to me by my one master, Megatron.
是我唯一的主人 威震天
Yes, him.
对 他嘛…
Sadly Megatron is no longer with us.
很不幸 威震天已经离我们而去了
Impossible.
不可能！
Why is it so difficult for everyone to accept?
为什么所有人都难以接受事实？
Skyquake, I located you,
天震 是我把你找到
I awakened you,
是我把你唤醒
thus I, lord  Starscream,
所以我 红蜘蛛陛下
am now your master!
现在是你的主人！
It has been a while, Skyquake.
好久不见 天震
Optimus Prime,
擎天柱
I haven't seen you since the battle of Technar.
在泰科纳战役之后我就再没见过你
Megatron ordered me to annihilate you.
威震天命令我来消灭你
That was a long time ago.
那都是陈年旧事了
That may be, Prime.
或许是 擎天柱
But my order still stand!
但命令还是要执行的！
Is this ancient war still worth fighting,
这古老的战争还值得打下去吗？
when so many comrades have been lost,
那么多同伴悄然离去
and worlds destroyed?
那么多星球毁于一旦
If you want to be a true leader, Starscream,
如果你想成为一个真正的领袖 红蜘蛛
then stray from Megatron's path,
那就不要走威震天的老路
and lead the Decepticons toward peace.
你要带领霸天虎走向和平
I would be willing to consider a truce,
我会真心考虑停战的
if you would be willing to bow before me, Optimus Prime.
只要你真心向我称臣 擎天柱
Again? Bow to this!
又是称臣？称称这个沉不沉！
Skyquake, this is a new era, on another world,
天震 这是一个新时代 一个新世界
side with the Autobots and help me end this conflict forever!
加入汽车人这边 帮我彻底终结这场战争吧！
I will never side with a Prime! Ummmaaa...
我永远不会与你们为伍！
What need have I for peace when I have Skyquake?
既然有了天震 我还要和平干嘛？
With some discipline
教训他一下
he will learn to respect his new master.
他就会懂得尊敬他的新主人
And once it becomes known that Skyquake destroyed Optimus Prime under my command,
只要他们知道 天震在我的命令下消灭了擎天柱
all Decepticons will gratefully bow to me.
全体霸天虎都会对我心悦诚服！
Bumblebee, no!
大黄蜂 不！
Do not miss a single moment, Soundwave!
一刻也不要漏掉 声波！
We shall need a visual documentation of Optimus Prime's demise, for the historical record.
我们要为擎天柱的辞世拍个纪录片 以儆后人！
Skyquake has not yet acquired a vehicle mode.
天震还没有扫描伪装形态
Fall back!
后撤！
So time has made you a coward, Prime?
年纪越大 胆子越小吗 擎天柱？
Let's see, where is it?
我看看 在哪呢？
You'll find out.
到时候你就知道了
But Ratchet,
可是…救护车
shouldn't I be doing the work?
我不是该自己动手吗？
Yi, yap, yap, yap... Don't touch! Just watch. And learn.
别动！看着就行了 学着吧
So we'll just go help Jack and Miko finish their...
那我们去帮杰克和神子完成他们的…
Without my supervision?
在我的监督之外？
You want them to be right, don't you?
你们也想做到最好吧？
Then watch a master at work!
那就欣赏大师的手笔吧！
Control freak!
控制狂！
We've lost sight of them.
他们已经出了视线范围！
Soundwave! Why aren't you tracking them!
声波 你怎么不去追踪他们？
What, what is it?
什么 怎么回事？
A second Decepticon life signal?
又一个霸天虎的生命信号？
But Skyquake is the only sleeper buried in this area.
但天震是唯一在这个地区待命的
The site of our destroyed Space Bridge?
在我们被毁掉的太空桥那里？
You are not telling me
你不是想说
that life signal belongs...
那个生命信号属于…
to Megatron?
…威震天吧？
B, b, b... but he was microns from the detonation point.
可…可他离爆炸点太近了
Nothing could have survived that blast!
没人能在那样的爆炸中生还！
Your sensors must be faulty.
你的传感器一定有问题！
Ignore the contact.
别理它！
Delete the coordinates!
把坐标删除！
Eh what am I saying?
唉 我在说什么呢？
Of course, this must be investigated.
当然了 去调查一下也无妨
If Lord Megatron is up there,
如果真的是威震天陛下
I shall bring him home.
我就去前往迎驾
Remain here and monitor the outcome.
呆在这里监视情况
When Skyquake snuffs Prime's spark,
等天震毁灭擎天柱火种的那一刻
I must bear witness.
我要亲自验证
"...must bear witness."
“…要亲自验证”
T6A to central command.
T6A号呼叫指挥中心
We are picking up transmissions originating from un-identified technology possibly hostile.
我们监测到来自不明物体的信号 可能是敌军
We are moving to investigate.
我们正前去调查
Negative T6A,
不行 T6A！
this is special agent William Fowler intercepting.
我是特工威廉・福勒
Strike your report from the record,
删除你的报告记录
and provide the origin coordinates.
向我提供源坐标
I'll take it from here.
我会去处理的
It will be a shame to crush you, bug,
把你砸扁真是大材小用 小虫子
but it is my duty.
但这是我的职责
Excellent strategy, Bumblebee.
好计谋 大黄蜂！
Skyquake, stay down.
天震 老实趴着吧！
Fowler?
福勒？
Agent Fowler, fall back!
福勒探员 快撤退！
Well, I'll be a bald eagle.
这下我算开了眼了
Air superiority achieved.
已获得制空权！
Stealing plans for a classified military aircraft will not be tolerated on my watch!
在我的眼皮底下盗取机密军用飞机设计 我决不容忍！
Heat seekers!
热能追踪导弹！
I still got it.
别想追上我！
No one could have survived this.
没人能在这里生还
The last thing I need now are rumors that Megatron is still...
我现在最不想听到的谣言就是 威震天还…
Megatron...
威震天…
But how?
怎么会这样？
Everyone believes you are deceased.
所有人都以为你已经仙逝了
Who am I to disappoint them, master?
我怎么忍心让他们失望呢 主人？
And this time, stay dead!
这一次 永远安息吧！
Soundwave, if you are listening,
声波！你听见了吗？
I have found Lord Megatron.
我找到威震天陛下了
And he is... unwell.
他情况…不太乐观
We must transport him to sick bay,
必须把他送到治疗舱
immediately.
要快！
Agent Fowler, we require immediate assistance!
福勒探员 我们请求立刻支援！
Anytime, fellow.
不用谢 伙计
Ground force coming fast!
马上要着陆了！
How're the landings, Con?
着陆快乐 虎子
Had Skyquake chosen to stray from his master's path,
如果天震没有步他主人的后尘
we might not be burying him today.
我们今天就不会置他于死地了
Bumblebee, putting yourself at risk was perhaps not the wisest of strategies,
大黄蜂 让你孤身冒险也许不算是上策
but you performed admirably.
但你的表现令人钦佩
there you are.
你们回来了！
Well, how are my, eh, our projects received?
快说 他们觉得我的 呃…我们的作业怎么样？
Well...
这个嘛…
Miss Nakadai, what planet would that be?
仲代小姐 那是哪个星球？
Em, Cybertron?
嗯…塞博特恩啊
It's... large, Mr. Darby,
它…个头不小 达比先生
but, is it operational?
可它能运行吗？
I hesitate to ask, Mr. Esquivel,
不知道该不该问 埃斯基维尔先生
but, eh, is it active?
不过…这是活火山吗？
Well, on our planet
哼 如果在我们的星球
you would have been awarded the highest honors.
你们会获得最高分的！
I get absolutely no credit!  Let's see if I help them.
我就不该参和进来！再也不帮忙了
Indeed, Bumblebee,
说得对 大黄蜂
our human friends would have been wise to stray from Ratchet's path.
我们的人类朋友不该走上救护车的老路
The troops will be pleased to hear of our success
知道威震天陛下情况稳定
in rushing Lord Megatron into stasis.
士兵们一定会很高兴的
Let us hope that our master pulls through.
但愿我们的主人能挺过这一关